### Contact

Pattanath 9037866074 (Mobile) rishadb7@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/rishab7 (LinkedIn) www.freelancer.in/u/rishadbabu (Portfolio)

## Top Skills

Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)

Amazon EC2

Amazon Relational Database Service (RDS)

### Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
Malayalam (Native or Bilingual)
Arabic (Elementary)
Hindi (Limited Working)

### Certifications

Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching (CCNA)

Cisco Certified Network Professional Routing and Switching (CCNP-RS)

# Rishad Babu

SDE at deskiplatforms | Full Stack(PERN) | REACT | Nodejs | POSTGRES | AWS(Lamda,API gateway,RDS,Event bridge,EC2, etc) | GCP | GIT | FIREBASE | PHP(Codelgniter) | ANDROID(Java) | IOS(Swift) |

Malappuram, Kerala, India

# Summary

I have a great experience in the web programming, Mobile App, Also, I had projects concerned with server administration on the Win and UNIX platforms.

Over the past 10 years, I have worked on many web projects using various web technologies, including Nodejs, PHP, MySQL, Postgres, firebase database, Javascript, React JS, React Native, HTML, CSS, and XML.

I have done the development & design of Mobile Applications using technologies like Android SDK.

My competencies lie in: - Complete the website according to client requirements.

- Improve the site performance(SEO, Improve Loading Speed, Browser Compatibility, User-Friendly Feature)
- Provide the best technical assistance to achieve client plan

I have good experience in the following areas:

Shopping Cart Frameworks: OpenCart

Framework / Platform / IDE - Android, Android Studio, Atom, Php Storm

Experience with ios development in swift

Experience with third party library in both ios and Android Experience with was services(RDS,EC2, LAMDA,API GATEWAY, AMPLIFY,APP RUNNNER ETC..)

# Experience

Hexcode Think Pvt. Ltd Software Engineer

January 2016 - Present (8 years 9 months)

Kerala, India

Hexcode think pvt ltd Software Engineer May 2021 - Present (3 years 5 months) Kochi, Kerala, India

deski platforms
Software Engineer
March 2021 - Present (3 years 7 months)

## Education

Government Engineering College, Sreekrishnapuram Palakkad Bachelor of Technology (BTech), Electronic and Communications Engineering Technology/Technician · (2010 - 2014)

Government Engineering College, Sreekrishnapuram Palakkad Bachelor's degree, Electronics and Communications Engineering · (2010 - 2014)

University of Calicut

Bachelor of Technology (BTech), Electronics and Communications

Engineering · (2010 - 2014)